europeana.eu 2019-12-11

# Privacy policy - Europeana Collections

Europeana Foundation collects, manages and uses your data so that we can run our services and share relevant content with you. This policy describes how we collect and use your data when you use our services through the website or in person, and the measures we take to ensure your data remains secure.

## Keeping your data secure

Your privacy is important to us. We take all steps necessary to ensure that your data is stored securely and used only in accordance with the preferences you have requested. We will not share your data unless you have given us permission to share it. We do not and will not sell your data. Where possible, we use services that are hosted within the European Union.

## Collecting your data

### What we collect

When you use one of our online services, apply to join the Europeana Network Association, or attend an event, we may ask you to provide us with some information. 

The information we collect or receive includes personal information such as your name, your email address, your profile picture, and any social media or third party services you have told us you would like to be associated with. We may also ask you to tell us information about your specific interests. 

### We collect information through forms

When you complete a form we have shared with you, you may be asked to submit your name and email address. 

When you apply to join the Europeana Network Association you will be asked to submit information that includes your name, email and organization. You may choose to also submit photographs and other relevant information. 

We may also collect information about your activities offline, such as when you attend an event, respond to surveys or speak to us by telephone. 

### We collect information through cookies

When you use a Europeana website, we use [cookies](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie) to collect information about your settings and preferences so that these can be used each time you visit one of our websites. We also collect information that is not specific to your identity such as information collected automatically through cookies, e.g. your language preferences. 

## Managing your data 

The first time you directly supply personal information, we create a record of your data and store that record in our internal systems. If you are a member of the Europeana Network Association, your record will be allocated a unique identification number. 

The records we store will be used to enable us to provide our services to you and send you communications that you may find useful, but only in accordance with your submitted preferences. 

The information collected automatically through cookies and log files is stored on our server. 

You can manage cookies by checking the settings for each browser you use.

We do not keep your data for any longer than necessary to fulfil the purposes for which we collected the data or the purposes for which data are reused. 

You may ask us whether we process data relating to you, and if so, which data this concerns. In that case, we can provide you with access to the data processed by us that relates to you. If you believe your personal data has been processed incorrectly or incompletely, you may request that we change or supplement the data (rectification). 

You can contact us via [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#bed7d0d8d1fedbcbccd1cedbdfd0df90dbcb). 

If you have a complaint concerning the processing of your personal data by Europeana Foundation, please 

  1. contact us via [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#3d54535b527d58484f524d585c535c135848);
  2. contact your local Data Protection Authority (DPA).

##  Using your data

There are a number of ways that we may use or share your data in order to provide our services. If we intend to use or share your data for purposes other than those described here, we will inform you when we request your data. We will only use your data upon your approval and/or if it is necessary to perform agreements. 

### Europeana Network Association 

When you are a member of the Association, your name and other non-personal information such as your organisation, country or sector, are published online. You may also publish additional personal information about yourself upon request. 

### Delivering and improving our services 

When you participate in a ticketed event, we will share your name, and sometimes your email address and other non-personal information with the other attendees at that event. 

When you sign up to a newsletter or one of our other services, we will use your data to deliver these services. 

The information we collect through cookies and log files is used to analyse the use of our services to help us improve them. We also use cookies to collect information that we can use to track performance and to make our services function better. 

### Administration

We use your contact details to send you information about the operation of our services, or changes to our policies, terms and conditions. 

###  Analytics

#### Hotjar

We use Hotjar in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimise our services. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users’ experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behaviour and their devices (in particular a device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymised form), screen size, type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymised user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy).

You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this opt-out link. 

#### Google Analytics

We also use Google Analytics to understand our users’ needs and optimise our service (e.g. how many views each page receives, whether people return to our website, what routes people take through our web pages). Google Analytics only stores anonymised information, such as browser type, operating system, visit time, country of access and anonymised IP addresses. Google Analytics data is stored in accordance with their own privacy policy, which is available by [clicking here](https://policies.google.com/privacy). 

##  Your privacy choices

## Email

We want to email you only if you want to hear from us. We try to keep the number of our emails to a minimum. We only email you according to the preferences you have submitted to us and we ensure that you can easily opt out of any emails you receive from us. 

We may send you service-related announcements when it is necessary to do so. 

### Accessing or editing your data

If you wish to access or edit your data or withdrawing your consent, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4b22252d240b2e3e39243b2e2a252a652e3e).

## What this policy applies to

This privacy policy applies to the use of services provided by Europeana Foundation. It is in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (Algemene Verordening Gegevensbescherming). [Previous versions of this policy can be viewed here](https://docs.google.com/document/d/14EV29hgB3TDOR7rXPotTIGNgjC_lESxobfrtG843Jh8/edit). 

## Updates

This page was last updated 24 May 2018. If you have any questions for us or suggestions on how to improve the information on this page, please use our [contact form](http://www.europeana.eu/portal/en/contact.html) to get in touch.
